# ROHITH RADHAKRISHNAN

+91 9496821962 namasterohith@gmail.com github.com/namasterohith linkedin.com/in/namasterohith

### **PROFILE**

Web and hybrid mobile app full-stack developer turned product person with more than 7+ years of experience predominantly in startups, working 5 years as an engineer and 2 years in product and engineering leadership roles.

Looking to help make great products in a technical product management role.

The satisfaction from making or fixing something is the driving force for me.

## SKILL SET

#### **PRODUCT**

- Requirement analysis and realisation of ideas to projects from scratch.
- Product design and development planning, roadmap creation and upkeep.
- Hands on experience with development, operations, maintenance & scaling.
- Efficient communication between end users, stakeholders and developers.
- Planned budget and timelines. Managed risks, costs and deviations.
- Created teams and hired for roles within the given budget.
- Managed SDLC with Scrumban hybrid model. Participated in different projects using waterfall and agile models including Scrum and Kanban.
- Technical & product team management using tools like,
  - o Jira, Asana, Trello, Confluence.
  - o Figma, XD, Invision.

#### TECHNICAL

#### Hands-On

- Languages: JavaScript (ES5, 6+), TypeScript, HTML, CSS.
- Frameworks & Libraries: Angular, Vue, Ionic, jQuery, Sass, Bootstrap.
- IDEs: VS Code, Android Studio, XCode.
- Tools: NPM, Yarn, Webpack, Docker, Gulp, Grunt, Capacitor.
- Version Control: Git, Git Flow.

#### Hands-Off/Novice

- React, Java, Spring(Boot), NodeJS, MongoDB, MySQL, Redis, Queues.
- Automated QA, Shell scripts, CI/CD Jenkins, Containers & Cloud.

## **EXPERIENCE**

As a software engineer, I worked with different technologies across the full stack in frontend, backend, hosting and mobile.

But working on the frontend, building hybrid mobile and web apps was my forte.

Having been a founding member of a startup, I have designed, planned and delivered products from scratch within the given budgets and timeframes.

# **Zporty (Zporty Ltd.), Remote (N. Ireland, UK)**Cofounder & CTO

JULY 2020 - PRESENT, (CTOaaS for MVP: AUGUST 2018 - MAY 2019)

- Founding member with cross functional responsibilities including budgets.
- Led pilot, MVP as lead consultant and launched the product as CTO.
- Managed end to end processes including product design, development and roll-out from scratch, subsequent feedback analysis, pivoting and growth.
- Led a team of 15 in designing, developing and rolling-out to the cloud.
- Managed development using a large tech stack across teams working with: Vue, React, Ionic, SpringBoot, NestJS, Redis, S3, Docker, Jenkins etc.

## Nexquare (Etwo Education Technologies Pvt. Ltd.), Kochi, India Fullstack Developer

MAY 2019 - JULY 2020

- Developer working with Angular, Spring MVC, MySQL, Ionic, Cordova.
- Worked independently under the product lead to evolve and scale products.
- Research & implementation of solutions to critical roadblocks in the school management product's growth and migration to SaaS model.
- Built initial phases of a new vertical now known as Nexopay mobile app.

# ConceptOwl (RankSurge Learning Pvt. Ltd.), Trivandrum, India Frontend Developer

APRIL 2016 - MAY 2019, (Frontend Consultant: AUGUST 2018 - MAY 2019)

- Web, Hybrid mobile app developer working with AngularJS and Ionic framework. Wrote APIs in Ruby On Rails.
- Worked with a small volatile team, fast paced environment with flat hierarchy, guided juniors.
- Built, maintained and documented:
  - $\circ$   $\,$  Web, mobile apps, website, and control panel for B2B customers.

# NewAgeSMB (NewAgeSys Solutions Pvt. Ltd.), Kochi, India Jr. Front End Developer

AUGUST 2015 - MARCH 2016

- Web, Cordova mobile apps developer using AngularJS and Ionic framework.
- Worked with a team of experienced veterans catering to software needs of clients, consisting of small and medium enterprises, building:
  - o Brand Websites, mobile apps catering for multiple platforms.

# **Student Startup, EDC - Mbits, Ernakulam, India** Founding Team Member - Web Development Service

MAY 2014 - AUGUST 2015, (part-time as a student)

• Created online presence for businesses using websites and social media.

## **EDUCATION**

#### Bachelor's Degree - Computer Science & Engg.

2011-15, Mahatma Gandhi University, Kerala, India.